Indiana University Board of Student Publications records, 1946-1966 C228 (1 box)
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University Board of Student Publications records
1946-1966
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. Board of Student Publications
C228 (1 box)
.6 cubic feet
The Board of Student Publications was established by the IU Board of Trustees on September 5, 1946, as it was thought that increased enrollment triggered by the G.I. Bill of Rights would cause a demand for more student publications. The primary function of the Board was to formulate policies on matters such as budgetary issues, the hiring of student staff, and general business procedures. The collection is organized in one series, Meeting files. Each folder contains the minutes corresponding to the meeting date on the folder as well as correspondence, memos, reports and newspaper clippings relating to that meeting.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Advance notice is required.
Administrative History
The Board of Student Publications was established by the Indiana University Board of Trustees on September 5, 1946, superceding the Arbutus Board of Control. According to R.L. Shoemaker, the Dean of Students in 1945, increased enrollment triggered by the G.I. Bill of Rights would cause a demand for more student publications. This board would supervise all student publications, making them more manageable by the University and more accessible to the students.
The Board was comprised of faculty from the School of Business, School of Journalism and Department of English. There were also members from the News Bureau, the Office of the Treasurer, the Student Activities Office, editors of the Indiana Daily Student, the Arbutus, two students elected by the Student Council, and the Dean of Students, ex-officio. The function of the board was to formulate policies on matters such as budgetary issues, the hiring of student staff, and general business procedures.
Before its circulation, any publication first had to be approved by the Board. The Board would examine the content of the publication and then approve or disapprove the publication. While the School of Journalism was in charge of the Indiana Daily Student, the paper was nevertheless required to run their business procedures through the Board.
In March of 1955, members of the Arbutus began discussing the idea of acting as a business independent of the Board. However, it was decided that the Board had the right to delegate any decisions made by the Arbutus staff because of the original goals the Board of Trustees set as well as the university procedures.
In June of 1969, the Board of Trustees agreed that the Board of Student Publications would meet twice a year to appoint the editor of the Indiana Daily Student. The authority to make decisions on all other business operations was returned to the organizations.
Arrangement
Organized in one series, Meeting files.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is organized in one series, Meeting files, arranged chronologically. Each folder contains the minutes corresponding to the meeting date on the folder as well as correspondence, memos, reports and newspaper clippings relating to that meeting.
Acquisition Information
Accessions 0215 and 7018.
College publications --Indiana --Bloomington.; College students' writings, American --Indiana --Bloomington.; Indiana University. Board of Student Publications -- Archives; Indiana University. Board of Student Publications -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University. Board of Student Publications -- History -- Sources
- Meeting files, 1946-1966
  - September 5, 1946
  - December 12, 1946
  - April 3, 1947
  - May 5, 1947
  - June 2, 1947
  - July 22, 1947
  - October 16, 1947
  - March 2, 1948
  - April 8, 1948
  - May 18, 1948
  - August 13, 1948
  - November 10, 1948
  - February 22, 1949
  - October 19, 1949
  - January 5, 1950
  - April 5, 1950
  - April 26, 1950
  - May 26, 1950
  - October 19, 1950
  - February 13, 1951
  - September 26, 1951
  - October 22, 1951
  - April 3, 1952
  - September 12, 1952
  - February 5, 1953
  - April 16, 1953
  - June 10, 1953
  - April 9, 1954
  - June 16, 1954
  - June 28, 1954
  - October 15, 1954
  - December 10, 1954
  - January 21, 1955
  - February 7, 1955
  - February 14, 1955
  - February 21, 1955
  - February 25, 1955
  - March 2, 1955
  - March 10, 1955
  - March 15, 1955
  - May 18, 1955
  - June 27, 1955
  - September 30, 1955
  - December 5, 1955
  - January 9, 1956
  - February 6, 1956
  - February 11, 1956
  - May 3, 1956
  - May 24, 1956
  - November 5, 1956
  - December 3, 1956
  - January 7, 1957
  - February 4, 1957
  - March 2, 1957
  - April 1, 1957
  - May 6, 1957
  - June 6, 1957
  - September 30, 1957
  - November 4, 1957
  - December 2, 1957
  - January 6, 1958
  - February 3, 1958
  - March 1, 1958
  - March 3, 1958
  - April 28, 1958
  - November 3, 1958
  - December 1, 1958
  - January 5, 1959
  - February 2, 1959
  - March 14, 1959
  - October 21, 1959
  - March 19, 1960
  - December 12, 1960
  - September 29, 1961
  - January 12, 1962
  - July 20, 1962
  - August 20, 1962
  - September 11, 1962
  - December 6, 1962
  - June 5, 1963
  - October 28, 1963-December 2, 1966